How long ago did they go in?
他们多久以前进去的？
BENTON: Some time ago, sir.
有段时间了, 长官
Tracy followed them as far as the official
boundary of the railway sidings.
Tracy 跟着他们一直到了铁轨的外墙边上
They went in about an hour ago.
他们半个小时前进去的
- Is Tracy still round there?
- Yes, sir.
- Tracy 还在那附近吗？  - 是的, 长官
- Right, stick around for a while.
- Just a minute, sir.
- 好, 继续还待在那里  - 等一下, 长官
Yes, what is it, Benton?
好, 什么事, Benton？
The Doctor and the boy.
They're coming out, sir, with Vaughn.
是博士和那个男孩, 他们出来了, 长官, 同 Vaughn 一起
They've all got into Vaughn's private car.
他们都进了 Vaughn 的私人轿车
Oh, they're driving off, sir.
噢, 他们开走了, 长官
- Is any force being used?
- No. Not that I can see.
- 有武力胁迫吗？  - 没有, 我没有见到．
Packer was there,
but it all seemed very friendly to me.
Packer 也在, 但在我看来似乎还比较友好
Shall we follow?
我们要跟住吗？
No, I'll have them tracked more discreetly.
Over and out.
不, 我会安排更加隐蔽的跟踪。完毕, 挂了
- Sergeant Walters.  - Yes, sir?
- Walters 中士  - 是, 长官
- Alert all area patrols in section three.
- Yes, sir.
- 通知第三组的所有区域巡逻队  - 是, 长官
- Did you hear all that, Jimmy?
- I did, sir.
- 你都听到了吗, Jimmy?  - 听到了, 长官
Look, we'll get you aboard a chopper,
and you can rendezvous with the tracking agent.
我给你安排一架直升飞机, 你就可以与负责跟踪的人汇合了
All right, sir.
好的, 长官
(ROTORS WHIRRING)
Yes, they've just gone into the IE area, sir.
好, 他们已经进入了 IE 的区域, 长官
- Shall I follow?  - No, circle the area.
- 我要跟进去吗？  - 不, 在那里盘旋．
We can't really do anything
until we get a request from the Doctor.
除非我们收到博士的请求, 否则我们什么也不能做
- Standing by, sir.
- And, Jimmy, keep out of sight.
- 待命中，长官  - 还有，Jimmy，保持在他们视线之外
If Vaughn's private army see you,
they might well get the wind up,
如果 Vaughn 的私人武装看到你们，他们可能会搞事
and that might make things rather unhealthy
for the Doctor and the boy.
这可能会让局面对博士和那个小伙子不利
Hey!
嘿
- Doctor, it's...  - Confusing, isn't it?
- 博士，这...  - 分不清了，是吧？
It's exactly the same as your office in London.
这跟你在伦敦的办公室一模一样
In all basic essentials, yes, it is.
所有基本要素都是一样的, 是的
That's the secret of my success, you see.
这是我成功的秘诀，知道吗
Uniformity. Duplication.
匀称，一致
My whole empire is based on that principle.
我的整个商业帝国都基于这个原则
The very essence of business efficiency.
业务效率的精髓
- Do sit down.  - DOCTOR: Oh, how kind.
- 请坐下  - 哦，有心了
I must say I'm rather glad
we have this opportunity to talk.
我必须要说我很高兴我们有机会进行这次谈话
Really?
真的？
I should, of course, be angry with you.
当然，其实我应该生你们的气
You've thwarted my elaborate
security precautions twice.
你们挫败了我精心制定的安全预防措施，两次
- I'd like to know why.
- Oh, that's quite simple.
- 我想知道为什么  - 哦，那很简单
I hate computers
and refuse to be bullied by them.
我讨厌电脑，拒绝被他们欺负
Your young friend Zoe.
你们的年轻朋友 Zoe
- Well, what about her?
- Well, she appears to have the same instincts.
- 哦，她怎么了  - 她似乎也有同样的直觉
She so confused one of my computers
she ruined its memory store.
所以她搞烂了我们的一台电脑, 毁坏了它的内存记忆
So that's why your thugs
dragged her and Isobel away.
所以这就是为什么你那些暴徒会把她和 Isobel 拖走
My dear young man, I wasn't angry with her.
我亲爱的年轻人，我没生她的气
On the contrary, I found the incident quite amusing.
恰恰相反，我发现这个事情很有意思
She's a remarkable girl.
她是个不寻常的女孩儿
And you, Doctor, are obviously a man
of no mean scientific ability.
而你，博士，显然是个科学能力不一般的人
Why do you say that?
你为什么这么说？
Well, my research department
found these quite fascinating.
哦，我的研究部发现这些东西很吸引人
There's a totally illogical factor
in their construction.
在它们的结构里面有一个完全不符合逻辑的部分
Are they of your own invention?
这是你自己发明的吗？
Ah, you're determined to guard your secret, I see.
啊，你下定了决心要保守你的秘密，我明白了
I don't blame you,
and I promise not to pry any more.
我不怪你，而且我保证不再打听了
- In fact, I'll do all I can to help you.
- Oh, how kind.
- 事实上，我会竭尽所能帮助你  - 噢，你真好
Now, you say you came here
looking for Professor Watkins
现在，你们说来这里是找 Watkins 教授
because you thought he might be able to help you.
说是因为你们觉得他也许可以帮助你们
Yes.
是的
Well, then I'll try to persuade him
to put aside his work and, um,
好，那我会试试, 看能否说服他把工作放一放
concentrate his efforts on your behalf.
聚焦到你的事情上
Make yourself at home.
请随意
Hey, look, you're not going to trust him, are you?
嘿，听着, 你没打算相信他吧，是吗？
- I mean, what about Zoe and Isobel?
- I haven't forgotten them, Jamie.
- 我是说，Zoe 和 Isobel 怎么办？  - 我没忘记她们, Jamie
They're in that box. I'm sure of it.
她们就在那里面，我敢肯定
Jamie, we're not going to help Zoe
by annoying Mr Vaughn, are we?
Jamie，我们惹恼 Vaughn 先生并不能帮上 Zoe，对吗？
I don't think you can annoy that man
even if you wanted to.
我觉得就是你想，你也没法惹恼那个家伙
He's being as nice as pie.
他的脾气很好
He's too nice.
他有点太好了
- Yeah, but why should he be?
- I don't know.
- 是，但为什么他会这样？  - 我不知道
He's a little bit too interested
in these circuits for my liking.
他对这些电路有点太感兴趣了, 我不喜欢
Hey, do you think he knows
about the Tardis, then?
嘿，那，你觉得他知道 TARDIS 的事吗？
Well, I don't see how he could do.
我看不出他怎么能知道
No, well, perhaps this Professor Watkins
will be able to tell us what's going on around here.
不能。也许这位 Watkins 教授能告诉我们这里在搞什么
- Yes, but that's what's worrying me.
- What?
- 是，但让我困扰的也是这个  - 什么？
Well, if Vaughn has anything to hide...
是这样，如果 Vaughn 有事情瞒着我们...
why is he letting us talk to Watkins?
他为什么会让我们跟 Watkins 谈话？
I'd think about it if I were you, Professor.
如果我是你，我就会考虑的，教授
After all, she is a pretty girl.
It'd be a shame to spoil all that.
毕竟，她是个漂亮的女孩儿，破坏这一点的话就就太惭愧了
What a vicious sadist you are, Packer.
你是个多么恶毒的虐待狂啊，Packer
I don't believe you, anyway.
我不相信你，不管怎样
I don't make idle threats, Professor,
as you well know.
我不会做无谓的威胁，教授，你是知道的
If you want to see that girl again in one piece,
如果你还想见到那个女孩儿完好无损话，
I suggest you do as Mr Vaughn asks.
我建议你按 Vaughn 先生要求的做
How do I know that you already
haven't harmed her, if you had got her.
我怎么知道你们还没有伤害她, 既然你们都抓住她了？
You can take my word for that, Professor.
你可以得到我对此的承诺，教授
(LAUGHING) Your word.
你的承诺
I know just how much value I can place on that.
我可知道它值多少钱
Harsh words, Professor, harsh words.
话说过份了啊，教授，过份了
Any progress?
有什么进展？
- So you haven't yet completed the machine?
- No, and I don't intend to.
- 看来你还没有完成这个机器  - 没，而且我也没打算完成
Oh, I think you will, Professor.
噢，我想你会的，教授
Much as I detest violence,
虽然我很讨厌暴力
I find it difficult to restrain Packer's
indisputable talent for persuasion.
我发现很难压制 Packer 那无可争辩的说服能力
Your niece is in our custody,
你侄女在我们的监管之下
and unless you do as I ask,
I shall hand her over to Packer.
除非你按我的要求去做, 否则我就把她交给 Packer
The choice is yours.
选择权在你
If I do cooperate, will you let her go?
如果我合作，你们会放她走吗？
Oh, no, she's our guarantee,
but she'll come to no harm.
哦，不会，她是我们的保证人，不过她不会受到伤害
All right.
好吧
- But I must see Isobel first.
- Of course.
但我必须先见到 Isobel  - 当然
Oh, there is just one other thing.
哦，另外只有一件事了
Don't look at me so suspiciously,
my dear Professor.
别用这种怀疑的眼神看我，亲爱的教授
It's merely that there are some friends
of yours here who wish to see you.
只不过这里有几位你的朋友想要见你
- Friends?
- Yes, they've gone to great pains to seek you out.
- 朋友？  - 是的，他们费尽周折要把你找出来
But I haven't been allowed visitors
since I came here.
但自从我到这里来，就不被允许会客
Why are you suddenly considerate?
你怎么突然这么贴心了？
I might tell them everything.
我可能把一切都告诉他们
Everything?
一切？
My dear Professor, you know nothing that can harm me.
亲爱的教授，你不知道任何对我不利的信息
Besides, there's always Isobel
to consider, isn't there?
再说了，总还得考虑 Isobel 吧，是不？
- Or would you rather leave her to me?
- No, no, Packer.
- 或许你更愿意把她留给我？  - 不，不，Packer
The Professor's going to do exactly as we ask.
教授会严格按我们要求的做
Aren't you?
对吧？
Yes, of course, I remember
Anne Travers telling me about you.
是的，当然了，我记得 Anne Travers 跟我说起过你
(Anne Travers 是老 Travers 教授的女儿，
在 05x05 The Web of Fear 一集中他们父女俩
与博士、UNIT一起对抗雪怪)
She was a student of mine,
you know, some years ago.
她是我的学生，你知道，多年以前
- Brilliant girl. Brilliant.  - Yes.
- 很有才华的女孩，很有才华  - 是的
Yes, they went to America, didn't they?
是的，他们去了美洲，是吗？
Oh, Travers was getting past it a bit, you know,
哦，Travers 有点老了, 你知道
and Anne persuaded him to go to America with her.
Anne 说服了他跟她一起去美洲
Oh, yes.
哦，是了
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Well, it's a long story.
啊，这就说来话长了
The strange Doctor
has been on another planet, Packer.
这个奇怪的博士到过其它星球，Packer
That's not possible!
那是不可能的
It is a fact, Packer.
这是事实，Packer
He has some sort of machine.
他有某种机器
Now let's see if we can
learn more about it, shall we?
现在我们来看看能不能了解到更多情况，好吗？
Switch on, Packer.
打开吧，Packer
With sound.
声音也打开
So we went to see Mr Vaughn,
所以我们去找 Vaughn 先生
and he said that you were working
on something important.
他说你在做一个重要的项目
I see. That's why you wanted to
leave them alone together.
我明白了，这就是为什么你要把他们俩单独留在一起
Exactly, Packer.
正是，Packer
(COMMUNICATOR HUMMING)
But the Doctor needed some help
on some electronic circuits that the Tardis had.
但博士需要有人帮忙弄一下 TARDIS 的电路板
- Really?  - Aye, aye.
- 真的？  - 是，是
Jamie, Jamie. I don't think
the Professor wants to hear about that.
Jamie，Jamie，我不觉得教授对这个感兴趣
Oh, on the contrary, what Anne told me
about the Tardis was most intriguing.
噢，恰恰相反，Anne 所告诉我的那些 TARDIS 的事情是最吸引我的
I'd like to hear a lot more about it.
我想多听一点关于它的事情
Professor, I think I should warn you
教授，我觉得我应该警告你
that Anne Travers allowed
her imagination to run a little wild.
Anne Travers 太放任她的想象力天马行空乱跑了
You mean to say that there is no such machine?
你是想说没有这样的机器？
- Of course there is...  - Jamie, I think
- 当然有...  - Jamie，我觉得
there are other more important things
to talk about at the moment.
现在这时候还有更重要的事情需要讨论
Oh, I see, yes.
哦，我明白了，是的
Professor, tell us about what you're doing here.
教授，告诉我们你在这里做些什么
Oh, it's very simple, really.
哦，很简单的事情，真的
I've been developing
a new kind of teaching machine.
我在研究一种新的教学机器
- Oh, yes? A teaching machine?
- What's it called?
- 哦，是吗？一种教学机器？  - 它叫做什么？
- I call it the Cerebraton Mentor.
- Oh, aye.
- 我把它叫做思维导师  - 哦，是
The main difference from other teaching machines
它与其它教学机器的主要差别
is that it's able to induce
emotional changes in the subject.
就是它能诱导测试对象的情绪变化
JAMIE: Oh.
噢
Our friend the Doctor is a resourceful man.
我们的博士朋友是个足智多谋的人
No wonder our allies fear him.
怪不得我们的盟友害怕他
- Our allies know him?
- Oh, yes, I was ordered to destroy him.
- 我们的盟友知道他？  - 哦，是的，它们命令我消灭他
But first I must learn the secrets
of this extraordinary machine of his.
但首先我必须掌握他那台非凡机器的秘密
If you're ordered to destroy him...
如果它们的命令是要消灭他...
I don't take orders, Packer. I give them!
我不接受命令，Packer，我只下发命令！
Now, I think the time has come
to stop playing games with this Doctor!
现在，我觉得是时候停止与博士玩游戏了!
But what can we do?
但我们能怎么做？
If, as you say, they have got Isobel
and your young friend,
如果，如你所说，他们抓住了 Isobel 和你那年轻朋友
then we're entirely at their mercy.
那我们就完全得看他们脸色了
No, no, not entirely.
There's my friend the Brigadier, remember?
不，不，也不尽然。还有我的准将朋友，记得吗？
- Do you think he can help us?  - Possibly.
- 你觉得他能帮助我们？  - 很可能
But quickly, tell me, what is Vaughn up to?
但是快点，告诉我，Vaughn 在图谋什么？
- What's he doing here?
- I know no more than you do.
- 他在这里做些什么？  - 我知道得不比你多
He's a ruthless man, without morals or principles.
他是个冷酷无情的人, 没有道德和原则
His object, I'm sure, is to get complete control
of the electronics industry of the world!
他的目标，我肯定，是要全面控制整个世界的电子工业！
I wonder.
我很好奇
I've a nasty feeling he's aiming
somewhat higher than that.
我有一种不好的感觉，他有某种比这更高的目标
Doctor, quick, somebody's coming.
博士，快，有人来了
Don't bother, Doctor.
别费事了，博士
Allow me.
让我来
Very ingenious. A simple magnet.
很天才啊，一块简单的磁铁
I congratulate you.
我祝贺你
Oh, how kind.
哦，谢谢
However, you must surely realise
但是，你肯定明白
that it's forced me to consider
other methods to make you talk.
这会逼我考虑其它方法来让你说话
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么？
Your friend Zoe is due to arrive here shortly.
你的朋友 Zoe 很快就该到了
So you have got her!
Listen, if you've harmed her in any...
看来你抓了她！听着，如果你伤害她一根...
You may still be adolescent enough
to make idle threats, young man,
你可以继续幼稚地做些空洞的威胁，年轻人
but I can assure you, I am not.
但我可以向你保证，我就不会
I want your travel machine, Doctor.
我要你的旅行机器，博士
Otherwise, I shall hand your friend Zoe
over to Packer.
否则，我就会把你的朋友交给 Packer
It's a simple choice, and shouldn't take you
longer than an hour to consider.
这是个简单的选择，应该不需要超过一个小时来考虑
Take them away, Packer.
把他们带走，Packer
- All right.  - All right.
- 好啦  - 好啦
Leave them to me. I'll take them.
把他们留给我，我来处理
Now, Professor, I suggest you continue with your work.
现在，教授，我建议你继续你的工作
Oh, dear. You know, Jamie,
I've always been rather scared of lifts.
噢，天。你知道吗，Jamie，我一直都很害怕电梯
Why?
为什么？
I never even like to start them.
我甚至从不喜欢启动它们
You will have to push the button for me.
你必须得替我按按钮了
Keep your mouth shut. Do as you're told.
闭上你的嘴。按吩咐的做
- Yes, Jamie. Do as you're told.
- Oh, yes...
- 是的，Jamie，按吩咐的做  - 哦, 好...
PACKER: Be quiet!
哦，好...   - 安静！
Packer! Mr Packer,
I obviously can't let you hurt Zoe,
Packer! Packer 先生，显然我不能让你伤害 Zoe
and so I'll have to tell you
all you want to know, now.
所以我只得把你们想知道的都告诉你们
You mean you're willing to talk?
你意思是你愿意说了？
Yes, I'm sure that Mr Vaughn would...
是的，我确信 Vaughn 先生会...
- Oh, there he is now...
- Quick, Doctor.
- 哦，他不来了吗...  - 快点，博士
Your knife.
你的刀
Your knife. Give me your knife.
你的刀，给我你的刀
- Why? What are you going to do?
- I'm going to try and break the circuit.
- 为什么？你打算做什么？  - 我要试试能不能破坏电路
What would that do?
那又会怎样？
Well, it will either stop the lift
or send us out of control.
唔，要么会让电梯停掉，要么我们会失控掉下去
But we're six floors up.
但我们在六楼上啊
We'll have to take that risk.
Hold tight, here we go.
我们必须担这个风险。抓紧了，我们走
(CLATTERING)
- Why are you so gullible, Packer?
- Just wait till I get hold of them. I'll...
- 你怎么这么容易受骗，Packer？  - 等我抓到他们，我要...
You'll do nothing!
I want them in one piece.
你什么也不要做。我要他们安然无恙
There was a 50/50 chance, you know, Jamie.
这里有 50对50 的几率，知道吧，Jamie
Yes, but what good has it done us?
哦，但对我们有什么好处呢？
I mean, we're stuck here in this lift now.
我是说，我们困在这个电梯里了
No. No, it's the lift that's stuck,
不，不，被困住的是电梯
not us. Look!
而不是我们。看！
Hey, where does that lead to?
嘿，那东西通到哪里？
Out into the lift shaft, I imagine.
Quickly, on me back.
通到电梯井外面，我估计。快点，到我后面去
You know something?
You're a clever wee chappie!
你知道吗？你是个聪明的家伙!
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHING)
Thank you, Jamie.
谢谢你，Jamie
Oh, my word!
哦，老天
Well, that's a long way up, isn't it?
啊，上去好远的路啊，是不？
Oh, well, we better get cracking
before they realise what's happened, eh?
哦，我们最好快点爬，一会儿他们就发现了
- Perhaps I'd better shut this.
- Aye.
- 也许我最好关上这个  - 是啊
(DOCTOR GRUNTS)
Hey, Doctor, I've just been thinking.
嘿，博士，我刚才在想
What happens if they get the lift going
before we get to the top?
我们到达顶楼之前，如果他们开动了电梯会怎么样？
- Oh, that's simple.  - What?
- 哦，那很简单  - 怎样？
- We get squashed.
- Oh. What! Well, come on!
- 我们会被撞死  - 噢，什么！那，赶紧啊！
Right!
对了
They've switched over the circuits.
The lift's working!
他们换了电路板，电梯可以工作了！
How splendid. Bring it up here.
很棒！开到这里来吧
Bring it up to the sixth floor.
把它开到六楼
(CLANGING)
Hey, that's not what I think it is, is it?
嘿，那不是我想的那样，是吗？
I'm very much afraid it is. Come on!
恐怕是的，快点！
- We'll never make it!
- Yes, we will! Come on!
- 我们到不了了  - 能，我们可以的。快点！
(LIFT CLATTERS)
What's happened?
发生了什么？
It's stopped! They must be checking.
它停掉了。他们肯定在检查
Come on, they may guess where we are
and come after us.
快点，他们可能在猜我们在哪儿，会来追我们
The engineer's certain...
工程人员很肯定...
- The shaft terminates in the roof, doesn't it, Packer?
- Yes, sir.
- 这个竖井通到顶楼，是吧，Packer？  - 是的，先生
- Why didn't you think of that?
- I'll get them!
- 你怎么没想到这个？ - 我去抓他们！
Call me when you do, Packer.
I'll be in my office.
抓到了就叫我，Packer. 我就在我的办公室等
And please don't fail this time,
there's a good fellow.
这次请不要失败了，那里面有个好家伙
They've started it again!
他们又开动了
Hurry, Jamie! Hurry!
快点，Jamie! 快！
- Come on, Jamie.  - Wait a minute, Doctor.
- 跟上，Jamie  - 等一下，博士
No, come on. Let's see where we are.
不，快点。我们来看看我们在哪儿？
- Now where?  - Down there.
- 现在去哪儿？  - 下去那边
JAMIE: Oh, no!
噢，不是吧！
Well, we can't go down the lift again, can we?
我们不能再搭电梯下去了，对不？
Hello. There's a fire escape. Come on.
哈罗，这里有个消防出口。快来
Oh, Packer, you do disappoint me.
噢，Packer。你真让我失望
They must have got down the fire escape, sir.
他们肯定沿着消防通道下去了，先生
And, of course, you didn't think
to have a guard on that!
而且，你当然没有想到派一个人守在那里！
- Well, normally...
- You're a stupid incompetent!
- 只是，通常...  - 你真是愚蠢无能！
I want that Doctor!
我要那位博士！
Put the whole compound on alert!
Have every available guard on the job!
整个园区发布告警！把所有警卫都派到这个事情上！
Find him, Packer! Find him!
找到他，Packer！找到他！
(ALARM BLARING)